<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senior Full Stack Web Systems Engineer on Marc Guyer</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/</link><description>Recent content in Senior Full Stack Web Systems Engineer on Marc Guyer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>/contact (Marc Guyer)</managingEditor><webMaster>/contact (Marc Guyer)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 09:42:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//marc.guyer.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 09:42:49 -0400</pubDate><author>/contact (Marc Guyer)</author><guid>//marc.guyer.me/contact/</guid><description>From POC to MVP to complete system architecture, I've got you covered from the frontend to the back. Ask me anything about your project - #span-3edb0907.cloaked-e-mail:before { content:attr(data-domain) "\0040" attr(data-user); unicode-bidi:bidi-override; direction:rtl; } &amp;#32;&amp;#32; var scriptTag = document.getElementById("script-3edb0907"); var link = document.createElement("a"); var address = "cram".split('').reverse().join('') + "@" + "em.reyug".split('').reverse().join(''); link.href = "mailto" + ":" + address; link.innerText = address.split('?')[0]; scriptTag.parentElement.insertBefore(link, scriptTag.previousElementSibling); scriptTag.parentElement.removeChild(scriptTag.previousElementSibling)</description></item><item><title>Mezzio Example: Functional Testing</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/posts/mezzio-example/functional-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 14:28:49 -0500</pubDate><author>/contact (Marc Guyer)</author><guid>//marc.guyer.me/posts/mezzio-example/functional-testing/</guid><description>Where do we start? It's a good choice to start any application with a solid structure for testing the application with automated testing tools. That's why the first post in this series is about testing. Any well-tested application will typically have more lines of testing code than actual application code. Starting with a good structure for testing will pay dividends down the road.
In this post, I'll show a basic setup for testing Mezzio applications.</description></item><item><title>Mezzio Example: Introduction</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/posts/mezzio-example/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 15:08:36 -0400</pubDate><author>/contact (Marc Guyer)</author><guid>//marc.guyer.me/posts/mezzio-example/introduction/</guid><description>What is this? Let's create a REST API with Mezzio. In this series, you'll learn how to create a REST API from the ground up. We'll use Mezzio as the base framework, Doctrine for the data layer, OAuth2 for authentication and authorization, PHPUnit for automated testing, and several other libraries along the way.
Source Code I've created a new bare-bones application starting with the Mezzio Skeleton Application where all the code shown in this series lives.</description></item><item><title>Example Recovery Procedure for MySQL Backup Made with Xtrabackup</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/posts/example-recovery-procedure-for-mysql-backup-made-with-xtrabackup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:09:56 -0400</pubDate><author>/contact (Marc Guyer)</author><guid>//marc.guyer.me/posts/example-recovery-procedure-for-mysql-backup-made-with-xtrabackup/</guid><description>We have a pre-existing procedure for backing up a MySQL database using hot backups with the wonderful Percona Xtrabackup and in this case the deprecated innobackupex binary.
Xtrabackup is nice since it creates a clean backup of InnoDB, XtraDB, and MyISAM tables quickly and without locking. There are countless useful features including point-in-time recovery, incremental backups, single table recovery, single partition recovery, I/O throttling, parallel processing, encryption, compression, streaming, and more.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>//marc.guyer.me/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 09:42:49 -0400</pubDate><author>/contact (Marc Guyer)</author><guid>//marc.guyer.me/about/</guid><description>Personal I have interests, it's true. In no particular order, here are a few:
Solving problems Flying - currently licensed with a single-engine land class rating Playing golf Solving problems Sleeping Waking up Solving problems I live in downtown Bloomington, Indiana, with Kate and JEFF!.
Professional The Past Way back in the year 2000, I cofounded Resite Information Technology. Amazingly as of this writing, that site remains up.</description></item></channel></rss>